大家下午好，
hey good afternoon everyone
嗯，我有几个关于
um I've had a few requests for a video
如何使用
on how to use
我猜张量板的视频的请求，
I guess tensorboard
当你在
to look at the logs of uh when you're
韩国 SS 为 Dreamboat
training uh with Korea SS for Dreamboat
Laura Greenwood TI 训练
Laura Greenwood TI one of the parameter
你设置的参数之一时，查看 uh 的日志 是日志文件夹，
that you set is the logging folder where
我们将在其中放置实际的训练
we're going to put the actual training
日志，以及您如何实际使用
logs and how do you actually make use of
它，所以这里有一个关于如何使用它的快速教程，
that so here's a quick tutorial on how
所以让我在这里打开一个
you do that so let me bring up here a
窗口，
the window
um
嗯，这通常是您使用的
so that typically is what you're going
如果你进入 Koyo SS 并且你
to get if you go into Koyo SS and you
开始我会得到我猜是带有常规
start I guess the GUI with the regular
uh gui.ps1 的 GUI 或你知道
uh gui.ps1 or GUI that that you know how
它如何工作的 GUI 你现在就去使用启动
it works right you go and use startup
学位你可以做什么让我们假装
degree now what you can do let's pretend
我有 从这里的 GUI 开始，如果您
I had started at the GUI here and you
想查看日志，有很多方法，
wanted to look at logs there's many ways
例如四种方法，如果您使用 visual
like four one if you're using visual
studio 代码作为进入
studio code as your kind of window into
终端和
the terminal and into the code within
存储库中代码的窗口，您可以单击此处加号来
the repo you can click on this plus here
实际 打开一个新终端，
to actually bring up a new terminal and
然后你可以
then you could launch the tensorflow
从那里启动 tensorflow，但假设你有一个
from there but let's say you have a
你正在使用的 um，就像
um you're using like the regular
Windows 的常规终端一样，你需要
terminal uh for Windows and you need to
导航并正确启动 tensorboard，
navigate and start the tensorboard right
所以你要做什么，所以我 我要去
so what do you do so I'm gonna go and
导航到我的 koias 文件夹所在的位置
navigate into where my koiass folder is
located
，我需要先激活，这是
and I need to activate first and that's
一个重要的部分，如果你坐在
an important part if you are sitting at
Powershell 提示符下并且你没有
the Powershell prompt and you don't have
任何东西 V 和 V Active
any anything there any V and V Active
那么它不会 工作得很好
then it's not going to work very well
你会尝试输入张量和
you're going to try to type tensor and
制表符抱歉插入制表符它不会
tab sorry insert tab it's not it's going
找到一大堆东西但它
to find a whole bunch of stuff but it's
不会出现在张量板上所以
not going to surface tensorboard so how
你如何解决这个问题你先激活你的
do you fix that is you activate your
venv 所以我' 我将继续
venv first so I'm going to go ahead
激活 denv，
activate the denv
以便激活 NVA 脚本，
so the NVA script activate
现在我已经激活了
and now that I've got my virtual
python 的虚拟环境，如果我开始
environment for python active if I start
键入 cancer T 和 S，我现在点击选项卡，
to type cancer T and S and I hit tab now
它将显示 tensorboard，所以现在
it's going to show tensorboard so now
你 知道 tensorboard
that you you know tensorboard is
实际上已经准备好使用了，现在有
actually ready to be used now there's a
一个参数你需要给它
one parameter you need to give it for
使用，你要去
use and you're gonna go and find that
在你的日志文件夹中找到那个参数，
parameter right there in your log folder
你只需去复制这个文件夹
and you just go and copy this folder
名称就可以了 为了将其引入
name and you're going to bring this into
CLI，我们将执行
the CLI we're going to do
tensorboard.exe space dash dash log dear
m-o-g-e-i-f-r 所以日志目录
m-o-g-e-i-f-r so log directory
基本上记录在那里并且你要在
essentially log there and you're gonna
双引号之间粘贴以防万一
paste between double quotes just in case
你的文件夹路径中有空格，
you have spaces in your folder path
呃你放 在双
right uh you put that between double
引号之间粘贴实际复制的
quotes you paste the actually copied
um 路径，然后按回车键，就是
um path and then you hit enter
这样，现在它将启动
and that's it now it's going to fire up
tensorboard，它将监听给
tensorboard and it's gonna listen on a
定的端口，我猜
given Port which should be uh I guess
这里显示的应该是 localhost
displayed here which would be localhost
6006。希望如此 我没有
6006. uh hopefully I didn't add
在我的另一个窗口检查中添加已经运行的传感器板
sensorboard already running in one of my
，是的，我有
other window check and yes I had
张量板，所以因为我已经
tensorboard so because I had it already
运行了它让我取消这个让
running let me cancel out this one let
我回到这里让我取消
me go back here let me cancel out of
这个所以我们没有 '不要让重复的
this so that we have we don't let like
duplicate
呃进程为同一个张
uh process fighting for the same
量板而战，现在我要重新启动它，
tensorboard now I'm going to restart it
现在我们要去看看
and now we are going to go and look at
它是什么样子，所以控制点击
what this looks like so control click on
这个东西会引发张量板
this thing is bringing up tensorboard
错误，现在你' 我
error behind and now you're gonna see
现在会在我的文件夹中看到它，我有一大堆
that in my folder right now I have a
whole bunch of logs for a whole bunch of
训练课程的日志，我做对了，所以
training sessions I did right so
tensorboard 会显示所有
tensorboard is going to show all of
这些，但是如果你想关注
those but if you want to focus on the
最后一次运行，你只需点击这里 全部取消选择
last run you just click here to unselect
它们，你会在张量板文件的末尾找到最后一次
them all and you're gonna find the last
尝试构建模型的运行
run of trying to build a model at the
，现在你
end of the tensorboard files and now you
可以查看那个，假设你
can look at that one and let's say you
想看看这次训练与
wanted to look at how did this training
之前的训练相比如何运行 我做的一个
run compared to the previous one I did
你可以去点击之前的
you could go and click on that previous
运行，现在它会过于像
run and now it's going to overly like
你在
the previous run that you did when you
运行你的训练时所做的上一次运行与新的运行所以
ran your training versus the new one so
现在你可以看到这一次显然
now you can see that this one obviously
少了很多或很多 更少或我
had a lot less or a lot fewer or steps I
可能在中间中止的步骤
might have aborted that run in the
也许我改变了我的参数所以它
middle maybe I changed my parameter so
做了更少的步骤我只是
it did a lot fewer steps where I just
提高了批量训练所以它只是一次
bumped up the batch training so it just
做八次而不是
instead of doing one it did like eight
一次做八次所以这就是为什么它是
at a time so that's why it's eight times
缩短了八倍，所以它会有所不同，但你
shorter so it will vary right but you
可以看看它
could you could look at various fronts
看起来是什么样的各个方面，这就是
of what it kind of looks and this is how
你如何使用张量板来跟踪
you can use tensorboard to kind of track
你的模型训练随着时间的推移，你
um your model training over time and you
可以比较不同的训练运行，所以
can compare different training runs so
看 例如，在这里我有点
see for example here I'm kind of
覆盖绿色和橙色，
overlaying the green and the orange and
你可以看到橙色
you can kind of see that the Orange is
有点高，所以
sort of higher so there is a higher or
与绿色会话相比有更高或损失，所以
loss compared to the green session so
这可以解释为说
this could be interpreted as saying that
也许训练 我在
maybe the training parameters I use for
绿色训练课程中使用的参数更好，
my green training session were better
因为它可以降低损失，但情况
because it led to lower loss it's not
并非总是如此，但通常情况下，如果您
not always the case but typically if you
在训练课程帐篷中的损失值较低，则
have a lower value for loss in the
training session
意味着您的训练参数
tent means that your training parameters
更适合训练数据
were better adapted to the training data
集 你正在做的让我们看看
set that you're working on let's see if
我是否在这里提出另一条现在你可以
I bring up another one here now you can
看到那种
see that that
紫色线实际上较低
kind of purplish line is actually lower
但它最终有点
but it kind of eventually sort of
与另一条对齐所以
aligned with the other one so not a
这里没有显着差异所以如何
significant difference here so how to
解释 这些东西是主题我的意思
interpret those things is subject I mean
是它本身就是一门科学
it's a it's a science on its own right
所以你实际上可以看看张量
so you can actually look at tensor
奖励所以这个你可以看到
rewards so this one you can see the
紫色通常较低所以所有
purple is typically lower so all of
这些东西都可以看并且你可以将
these things can be looked and you can
它们中的许多分层一个 在另一个之上
layer many of them one on top of the
并查看差异，这就是
other and look at the differences so
你现在如何使用 tensorboard
that's how you can use tensorboard now
你如何实际解释
how you actually interpret the results
tensorboard 的结果这真的取决于你
of tensorboard it's really up to you
在这里你可以看到适应
here you can see like the the adaptation
学习率
learning rate that was kind of scaled
随着时间的推移而缩放
over time like over a number of steps
您可以看到许多步骤，因此
you can see that so there's a whole
您可以在此处获得一大堆不同的日志信息，具体
bunch of different log information you
取决于为
can get here depending on what is being
模型明显记录的内容，
logged obviously for the model
嗯，是的，希望
um so yeah so that's it hope you guys
你们喜欢这就是如何获得
enjoyed that's how you can sort of get
张量板和 当你用完
tensorboard and when you're done using
它，你可能想看看
it and you want to maybe look at some
其他模型的其他日志训练，
other logs training for other models and
你就去这里，你控制 C，它
you just go here you control C and it's
会阻止 tensorboard 运行，
going to stop tensorboard from running
现在如果我尝试刷新它，甚至
and now if I try to refresh it or even
明显刷新它
refresh this obviously nothing's
那个端口上没有任何东西在监听，所以它
listening on that Port so it's just
只会失败所以这是一个快速的如何
gonna fail so that was a quick how to
运行张量板以及如何用
run tensorboard and how to kind of look
密集的词来看待不同的值
at the different values with intensive
希望这对你有所帮助，祝
words hope that was helpful and have a
大家度过愉快的一周再见
great week guys bye